live.
>> Welcome, brothers and sisters, to
another Israel of God Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the ten
commandments that God commanded the
world to keep. Brother Tanzel,
>> and God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which hath brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shall have no
other gods before me. Thou shall not
make unto thee any graven image, or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shall not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God, visiting the
iniquities of the fathers upon the
children, unto the third and fourth
generation of them that hate me, and
showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him giveth that taketh his name in
vain. Remember the Sabbath day to keep
it holy. Six days shall thou labor and
do all thy work. But the seventh day is
the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In it
thou should not do any work. Thou, nor
thy son, nor thy daughter, that man's
servant, nor that thy maid servant, nor
thy cattle, nor thy stranger that is
within thy gates. For in six days the
Lord made heaven and earth, the sea, and
all that in them is, and rested the
seventh day, when for the Lord blessed
the Sabbath day, and hollowed it,
honored thy father and thy mother, that
thy days may be long upon the land which
the Lord thy God giveth thee. Thou shall
not kill. Thou shall not commit
adultery. Thou shall not steal. Thou
shall not bear false witness against thy
neighbor. Thou shall not cover thy
neighbor's house. Thou shall not cover
thy neighbor's wife, nor his man
servant, nor his maid servant, nor his
ax, nor his ass, nor anything that is
thy neighbor. We read Exodus 21-17. May
the Lord have a blessing to the reading
of his words. In Jesus name we pray.
Amen. Amen.
>> Amen. So here on question and answer,
you can ask us a question and we will
answer it according to the King James
Bible. And if we cannot find an answer,
we will seek further counsel to give you
an answer at a later time. And keep in
mind all vague questions will not be
answered and all long scripture
questions will not be answered for
time's sake. We also ask that you keep
your questions to a two scripture at the
most minimum maximum but we may point
you in the direction of a CD or a DVD
that you can purchase by calling the
office. So for time's sake, we ask that
you be as direct as possible with your
questions so we can be as direct as
possible with our answers out of the
King James Bible. No other Bible will be
ex acknowledged on this program. This is
a live stream, so if you have any
questions, you can submit them at this
time. Let me introduce you to the family
that will take part in this e this
evening's panel. We got brother Jerome.
>> Rest in peace.
>> We got brother Julius.
>> Good evening everybody.
>> We got brother Tanzel.
>> Good evening everyone.
>> We got sister Deborah.
>> Good evening.
>> We got brother Sean.
We got the guest caller and I am brother
Andre. Sister Deborah, let us get
started with our first question of the
evening.
>> Uh yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Detroit Troy Price asked in Matthew 1
18-20,
who was Gabriel referring to when he
mentioned that which was conceived in
Mary was of the Holy Spirit being that
angels can procreate.
>> Yes, angels do not uh make babies. So,
let's go to that Matthew first chapter
and we're going to read verse 18.
Uh, go right ahead, brother Tanzel, when
you get it.
>> Now, the birth of Jesus Christ was on
this wine. When as his mother Mary was
expoused to Joseph before they came
together, she was found with child of
the Holy Ghost.
>> Yes. Go ahead. Then Joseph, her husband,
being a just man, and not willing to
make her a public example, was minded to
put her away privately.
>> Yes.
>> But while he thought on these things,
behold, the angel of the Lord appeared
unto him in a dream, saying, Joseph,
thou son of David, fear not to take unto
thee Mary, thy wife, for that which is
conceived in her is of the Holy Ghost.
>> Go ahead.
and she shall bring forth a son. Thou
shalt call his name Jesus. He shall save
his people from their sin.
Now all this was done that it might be
fulfilled which was spoken of the Lord
by the prophet saying. Behold, a virgin
shall be with child and shall bring
forth a son. They shall call his name
Emmanuel, which being interpreted is God
with us. So, nowhere in this passage did
it say an angel uh impregnated Mary.
What the angel did is do what he was set
to do. And let's go see what that is.
Let's go to John 16 and we going to read
verse 13 there. John 16 and 13.
John 16 and 13.
Go ahead when you get it, brother. How
be it, when he, the Spirit of truth, is
come, he will guide you into all truth,
but he shall not speak of himself, but
whatsoever he shall hear, that shall he
speak, and he will show you things to
come.
>> And that is what the angel did. Whatever
the angel heard, it spoke, and it spoke
to Mary and gave her the message as well
as Joseph. Now let's go to Revelation 1
and we going to read verse one there.
Revelation 1 and1.
Go ahead, brother.
>> The revelation of Jesus Christ which God
gave unto him
>> to show unto his servants things which
must shortly come to pass.
And he sent and signified it by his
angel unto his servant John. So what you
see right here is the revelation of
Jesus Christ, which the Father gave onto
him to show unto his servants things
which must shortly come to pass. And he
did it by
sending it by his angel
onto his servant John. And the angel
just spoke the word that was given to
him to speak.
That is it.
And well, I got to go here. Let's go
here. Psalm 33. Psalm 33. And we going
to read verse 6 and 9. And that'll be
it. Psalm 33:es
6 and 9. Go ahead, brother. By the word
of the Lord were the heavens made, and
all the host of them by the breath of
his mouth.
>> By the word of the Lord were the heavens
made, and all the hosts by the breath of
his mouth. Verse nine, go ahead.
>> For he spake and it was done. He
commanded and it stood fast.
>> So the word is spoken and is done. And
we just read in Revelation how this was
done and what the angel spoke and it
was. So I hope that helps. Is anybody
want to add?
If not,
>> let me throw in.
>> Yes, sir.
>> You know, it's talking about like uh
helping the holy the angels don't uh
procreate.
Now, that question was based on somebody
that don't believe that there is a birth
of Jesus. It is a virgin birth. Why
don't we go to Isaiah 7th chapter?
>> Yep.
>> And read who going and and we going to
start show you where a virgin going to
conceive.
>> Yes, sir.
Isaiah 7
>> and uh we going and we see the Lord
himself shall give you a sign.
>> 14.
>> Go ahead.
Therefore, the Lord himself shall give
you a sign. Behold, a virgin shall
conceive and bear a son, and shall call
his name Emmanuel.
Now,
the Lord himself shall give you a sign.
That mean that he going to do this
himself.
And let's go and show you in order for
him to do that, he needed something.
Let's go into Hebrews the 10th chapter.
We're going to read one and then we're
going to skip down to verse four and
continue.
>> Can we turn to guest caller uh volume
up?
>> Hebrews the first 10th chapter. Did you
say the 10th chapter? Guest caller.
>> Hebrews 1
and then skip down to four and continue.
Hebrews 10 and one. Right.
>> Right.
>> For the law having a shadow of good
things to come and not the very image of
the things can ever with those sacrifice
which they offer yearby year continually
make the comes there unto perfect.
>> Now skip down the fool and continue.
>> For it is not possible that the blood of
bulls and of goats should take away sin.
Wherefore when he cometh into the world,
he said, "Sacrifice and offering thou
wouldest not, but a body has thou
prepared me."
Now, what happened is he had a body that
was prepared for him to take over
cuz I already said a virgin going to
conceive. And to show you what what what
this is saying, let's go into Luke
the uh first chapter
and start reading at verse 30. Uh uh uh
uh verse 30.
>> And the angel said unto her, "Fear not,
Mary, for thou hast found favor with
God, and behold, thou shalt conceive in
thy womb, and bring forth a son, and
shall call his name Jesus."
>> And he shall and he shall be great, and
shall be called the son of the highest.
And the Lord God shall give unto him the
throne of his father David.
>> He should be called the son of the
highest. That's the son of God. Okay.
And God is the holiest of all the holy
spirit. Isn't that correct?
>> That's right.
>> The Lord said the book tell God said uh
the Lord God is a spirit and he is holy.
So now let's see. Keep reading. What's
it say? and he shall reign over the
house of Jacob forever, and of his
kingdom there shall be no end.
>> Now,
what did Mary say? Read the next verse.
>> Then said Mary unto the angel, but how
shall this be, seeing I know not a man?
>> How can this be? Being I never known a
man.
So now it's not a question of whether
angel repro uh procreate or God. Thing
about it is God made him a body
and he said God himself going to show
you a sign and and and all and told you
about the virgin. And what did he say?
Call his name Emanuel. Somebody read and
show me what Emanuel mean.
>> We read that
>> Isaiah 9.
Uhuh. We read that in Matthew 1. Matthew
1,
>> Matthew 1 and 23.
>> Behold, a virgin shall be with
>> you. Read it.
>> Go ahead. Uh, show where this is the
birth of Jesus. God is where
>> Luke one
>> Matthew Matthew 1 and uh 21 and 23
>> Matthew right that's right Matthew 1
>> go ahead man
>> Matthew 1 pick it up at verse 21
>> 21 y
bring
>> why don't we pick it up at 18. Now at 18
show who this is talking about.
>> Yes sir. 18.
>> Now the birth of Jesus Christ was on
this wide
when at his mother Mary was expoused to
Joseph before they came together and she
was found with child of the Holy Ghost.
But then Joseph,
her husband, being a just man, and not
willing to make her a public example,
was minding to put her work away
privately.
But while he thought on these things,
behold, the angel of the Lord appeared
unto him in a dream, saying, Joseph,
thou son of David, fear not to take unto
thee Mary, thy wife, for that which is
conceived in her is of the Holy Ghost,
and she shall bring forth a son, and
thou shalt call his name Jesus, for he
shall save the people from their sin.
Now all this was done that it might be
fulfilled which was spoken of the Lord
by the prophet saying, "Behold, a virgin
shall be with child. It shall bring
forth a son, and they shall call his
name Emmanuel,
which is which being interpreted is God
with us."
>> So now this coincide with what the Lord
said in in the Isaiah the 7th chapter,
>> right?
going to conceive. You going to call his
name Emmanuel. Emmanuel being God is
with us. Didn't it say that God himself
give you a sign?
>> Right. Right.
>> And God himself which which is Jesus we
talking about the one that created
everything at the commandment of God.
He's saying well he going to give you a
sign. Now when he came but he needed a
flesh and blood body. Didn't we read
that a body was prepared for him? Right.
>> Yeah.
>> Then and he took that body over and that
angel that that spirit that overshadowed
her, there wasn't that but an angel that
came and planted that body in her womb.
Now when he was born, God was with us as
he said, "God himself shall give you a
sign." So it don't have nothing to do
with an angel uh uh reproducing or
anybody else or even the father,
>> right? that the God can make man out of
dirt. You mean he can't make a body and
take it over.
>> Okay.
>> And come among this creation.
I just wanted to add that cuz I don't
like the implications.
>> Yes, sir.
>> I just don't
>> That's all I have to say.
>> Thank you, guest caller. Uh we we hope
we know that you got some understanding
in that one and we'll move on sister
Deborah to the next question.
>> Next question. Pauline R asks, "What
does the Lord mean in Isaiah 11 verse1
15?"
>> We're going to ask brother Julius to
answer that question. Brother Julius,
>> let's go there. Tenzil, but we going to
start at verse 11. Isaiah 11 and 11.
Isaiah 11. Then we'll read verses 15 and
16 because we got to date this. Go
ahead. And it shall come to pass at that
day that the Lord shall set his hand
against the second time to recover the
remnant of his people which shall be
left from Assyria and from Egypt and
from Pathro and from Kush and from Ilam
and from Shann and from Hath and from
the islands of the sea. So the Lord is
back and he's gathering all of his
people that are scattered. Skip down to
verse 15.
>> And the Lord shall utterly destroy the
tongue of the Egyptian sea. And with his
mighty wind shall he shake his hand over
the river and shall smite it in the
seven streams and make men go over dry
shard.
>> Go ahead. So uh he going to make pe men
go over dry. He going to close he going
to uh make men go over dry shard. People
gonna be coming from all over and they
gonna come from that way they gonna be
headed toward Jerusalem. Go ahead.
>> And there shall be an highway for the
remnant of his people which shall be
left from Assyria like as it was to
Israel in the day that he came up out of
the land of Egypt. So just like the Lord
opened up the Red Sea and let uh Israel
come through the Red Sea on dry land, he
going to do the same thing again when he
gathering the rest of the people. And he
going to uh dry up the land so they can
walk across dry shad and come on in
right all the way up to the land of
Israel.
He going he going to bring his people uh
uh uh into um uh from gather from all
the places that they have scatter uh uh
scattered.
Anybody want to add to that?
>> Thank you, brother Julius. Sister
Deborah, we'll move on to the next
question.
>> Moving on. Just no. Chill asks in Psalm
76 verse11,
"What are the presents to be brought to
God?" Is this talking about tithes?
>> We're going to ask Brother Jerome to
answer that question. Brother Jerome,
>> no, it's not talking about tithes.
It's actually talking about the u
people, the children of Israel. Okay.
But let's go read the verse that you
gave.
Psalm 76:1.
You get it? Go ahead.
>> Bow and pray unto the Lord your God. Let
all that be round about him bring
presence unto him that ought to be
feared.
>> Yeah. It's talking about uh when the
Lord return,
he going he going he going to beat down
the nations
and they going to have to free his
people cuz we still in this modern day
captivity even until this day. But when
he free his people, the nations going to
be bringing his people
trying to please the Lord, you know. So
he going to bring a present his people.
Okay. Uh but let's go to uh Isaiah
chapter 18 and we're going to read verse
3-7.
>> Isaiah 18.
>> Yeah. Pick it up at verse three and read
it to the seven.
>> Go ahead.
>> All ye inhabitants of the world and
dwelleth on the earth. See ye when he
lifted up an in sign on the mountain,
and when he bloweth a trumpet, hear ye.
For so the Lord saith unto me, I will
take my wrath, and I will consider my
dwelling place like a clear heat upon
herbs, and like a cloud of beauty in the
heat of harvest.
for a for the harvest when the bud is
perfect and the sour of grapes is
ripening in the flower and he shall both
cut off the sprigs and pruning hooks and
take away and cut down the branches.
>> You talking people is symbolic. It's
representing people. He going to do this
to the wicked. Go ahead. They shall be
left together unto the fowls of the
mountain and to the beasts of the earth.
And the fowls shall summer upon them.
All the beast of the earth shall winter
upon them.
>> At that time shall the the present be
brought unto the Lord of hosts of a
people scattered and peeled and from a
people terrible from their beginning
hitherto. A nation meeted out and tried
underfoot whose land the river has
poured for the place of the name of the
Lord of hosts, the Mount Zion.
>> Yeah. So people, the people of God, the
children of Israel, that's the present
that the other nations going to be
bringing, okay, to the Lord. And he
going to be bringing gold and silver,
too. You can read that in Isaiah the
60th chapter, you know, to the house of
the Lord. That's all I got on you.
>> Thank you, brother Jerome.
Sister Deborah, we will proceed with the
next question.
>> Next question. Veriah Ben says, "In both
Dan and Revelation, the great
tribulation will last for a time times
and a half, 1260
days and 42 months. What are the extra
days added in Dan 12 vers 11 and 12? And
what are we waiting for?
>> We're going to uh give this question to
the guest caller. Guest caller.
>> So the first thing is let's go read
Daniel 12 11 and 12.
>> Daniel 12 11 and 12.
Go ahead, brother Tanzel.
>> And from the time that the daily
sacrifice shall be taken away, and the
abomination that make it desolate set
up, there shall be a,290
days.
But blessed is he that waiteth and
cometh to the,35
and 30 days.
Now the the those days I have been
trying to figure out for years where
they go. What I'm not concerned about
those days. What I'm concerned about is
and you should be so concerned about is
that when they start the animal
sacrifice
and they going to build the temple
the over there and then the uh
pope going to move into that temple.
Now, that's what you concern yourself
with because that's what you going to
have to watch. Then you will know what
you have to do. Let's go to Matthew the
24th chapter
and read verses 15- 18.
Then we're going to skip down and read
verses 20- 20 21- 22.
Matthew 24:15 to 18 21-22.
So when ye there therefore shall see the
abomination of desolation spoken of by
Daniel the prophet, stand in the holy
place, who so readeth, let him
understand.
Then let them which be in Judea flee
into the mountain. Let him which is on
the housetop not come down to take
anything out of his house. Neither let
him which is in the field return back to
take his clothes.
>> Now that let you know the urgency of
this. When you see that it's so whenever
you see that it is time to move. Why?
Skip down to verse 21. Read 21-22.
For then shall be great tribulation,
such as was not since the beginning of
the world. To this time, no, nor ever
shall be, and except those days shall be
shortened, there should no flesh be
saved. But for the elect's sake, those
days shall be shortened.
Now, that is what you should be
concerned about because if you act on
that like you're supposed to, then you
will not have a problem. Go to 2
Thessalonians the 2 chapter.
Start reading at verse one. We're going
to read 1 to 6.
Now we beseech you, brethren, by the
coming of our Lord Jesus Christ, and by
our gathering together unto him, that ye
be not soon shaken in mind, or be
troubled, neither by spirit, nor by
word, nor by letters as from us, as that
the day of Christ is at hand. But let no
man deceive you by any means, for that
day shall not come except there come a
falling away first, and that man of sin
be revealed, the son of predition,
who oppose, and exalt himself above all
that is called God, or that is
worshiped, so that he is God, siteth in
the temple of God, showing himself that
he is God.
>> Go ahead.
>> But remember ye not that when I was yet
with you, and I told you these things,
and now ye know what withholdeth that he
might be revealed in his time. For the
mystery of iniquity do already work.
>> Now we let you know right now what you
do is you watch there and you watch the
animal sacrifice. You watch the temple
and when the pope move in it, you flee.
And like Paul said here, now I've told
you now he will be revealed in his time.
So that is when we uh that is what we
waiting for. We're waiting for the sign
until that time come.
You stay where you are cuz they ain't
nowhere safe. You go to Jerusalem, the
Lord say he going to flatten it when he
come.
You going to some of the African nation,
you steal uh uh uh uh the Hamites.
So the time what we're waiting for is
what we just what the book just told you
for the pope to move into the temple
that's going to be built. That's when
you flee.
That's all I have to say.
>> Yes, sir. Thank you for that uh answer.
Guest caller, sister Deborah, let us
move on.
>> Yes. Be alert as for you to explain how
Satan is a man in Ezekiel 28:9.
>> Let's go to Ezekiel 28 and we going to
read verse 9. Satan is not a man. Satan
is a cherub angel. But let's read it.
Ezekiel 28:9. Go ahead, brother.
>> Will thou yet say before him that
slayeth thee, I am God, but thou shalt
be a man,
>> no God in the hand of him that slayeth
thee.
>> Now, what we talking about here? You
talking about the prince of Tyrus and
then the king of Tyrus. But there's a
spirit behind that that the Lord is
talking about as well. So let's skip
down and read verse 12 there. Go ahead.
>> Son of man, take up a lamentation upon
the king of
>> Tyrus and say unto him, thus sayeth the
Lord God, thou sest up the son full of
wisdom and perfect in beauty.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Thou has been in Eden, the garden of
God, and every precious stone was thy
covenant. the sardash
topaz and the diamond, the burl, and the
onyx, and the jasper, and the sapphire,
and the emerald, and the carbunkle. And
gold, the workmanship of thy taverns,
and of thy pipes, was prepared in thee
in the day that thou was created. Now
the king of Tyrus and the prince of
Tyrus was not in the garden of Eden but
the one that is that they standing
behind is and let's see who that is.
Read the next verse.
>> Thou are the anointed cherub that
coverth
>> and I have set thee so thou was upon the
holy mountain of God. Thou was walk Thou
has walked up and down in the midst of
the stones of fire.
>> Go ahead.
>> Thou was perfect in thy ways from the
day that thou was created until iniquity
was found in thee.
>> So he talking about Satan right here,
but he is called the anointed cherub.
Now you might read that he was a man,
but that is the one the one behind that
man is Satan, the devil. But you also
read even the Lord. Let's go to Exodus
15. Exodus 15 and read verses 3 and 4.
Go ahead
when you get it. Exodus 15 3 and 4. Go
ahead.
>> The Lord is a man of war. The Lord is
his name.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And Pharaoh's chariot and his host have
he cast into the sea. His chosen
captains also are drowned in the Red
Sea.
>> They say the Lord is a man of war, but
God is not a man.
>> Right?
>> Let's see what he is. Let's go to uh
John the 4th chapter and read the 24th
verse and that will be it. John 4 and
24.
Go ahead.
God is a spirit and they that worship
him must worship him in spirit and in
truth.
>> So God is a spirit and cherub angels are
spirits.
So no, he's not a man.
That's all I got on that.
>> Right.
>> We'll move on to the next question.
Sister Deborah.
>> Yes. Next question. Um, Barbara Still
says,
"If right now
I've seen on TV that the abomination of
desolation,
where should I run to if it happens
right now?"
We're going to ask the guest caller to
shed some light on that even though he
already did, but we're going to ask him
to do to talk about that. Guest caller,
first thing is you ain't going to see
him right now.
He gave you all of the signs.
First thing you got to have animal
sacrifice.
You got to have a temple bill. Animal
sacrifice got to be stopped.
folk got to move into that temple and
that is when you uh to flee
and where you going the Lord tell you in
some is going to be the wilderness.
Where was the wilderness? It was in the
land of Midian which is uh uh uh
southwest Saudi Arabia right now.
>> Yes sir.
And as far as the transportation is
concerned, the Lord will provide. If he
can split a sea and bring Israel over
dry shard, then surely he will have some
way of transporting his people. So I say
to uh uh uh to sister, what you really
really need to do is make sure your head
stay on straight so you will understand
what you're looking at in the time that
you supposed to look at it and lead the
transportation to God.
That's all I have to say.
>> Thank you guest caller and uh sister
still we hope you got that
understanding. Sister Deborah, let's
move on to the next question. Moving on.
Tanya Ligan says, "If someone who came
into the truth while they are living in
a nursing home or a person is paralyzed,
is there a way for them to be baptized
in Jesus' name?"
>> We're going to ask the guest caller to
answer that question. guess caller
>> if there's always a way to do that. If
he's a male and he's circumcised or even
and and paralyzed and or either and also
a female if they are really serious and
they make a request,
we through the grace of God will figure
out how to baptize them.
But they have to make the request and
they have to be serious.
then we'll figure out how to get them in
the water. That's all I have to say.
>> That's right. Thank you, guest caller.
Sister Deborah, next question.
>> Next question. School email says in Luke
22:3.
It says Satan entered into the heart of
Judas. Does this mean evil thoughts can
come from both your mind and e and evil
angels? Or can evil angels only
influence your mind if you're evil?
>> We're going to ask brother Jerome to
shed some light on that question.
Brother Jerome.
>> Yeah. Um it don't matter whether you
good or evil. He He Satan
uh uh send send you some thoughts to try
to take you away from God. It don't make
it make a difference if you good or
evil. Okay? But uh there's other verses
to let you know um you can have a evil
thought even without Satan
influencing you, you know. Uh but let's
go read the verse that that you gave.
You gave Luke 22 and three. Let's let's
understand this. Luke 22 and3
go ahead and read it when you get it.
>> Then into Satan into Judas her name is
Scariot being of the number of the 12.
>> So you know Satan is influencing his
mind and we going to tie that with the
uh John 13 and2. Now understand
Judas, he didn't have to act on
what is being put in his mind. Be
like evil thoughts. You don't have to
act on them. You going to have evil
thoughts. Even when you go to sleep, you
can have an evil thought, you know, but
don't act on it. But Judas, he acted on
it. Okay? But let's go read John 13 and2
because it talks about Satan is
influencing his heart which is his mind
you know John 13 just read verse two
brother Tazil
and supper being ended the devil having
now put into the heart of Judas his
scariot Simon's son to betray him
>> so that's the evil thought he put into
his mind but he ain't had to act on it
but he
Okay. Now, let's go uh to one other
place and I'll be done. Let's go to
Ezekiel 38. This is a time where uh
Satan is is locked in the pit.
Okay? And
Israel is back home safely.
You know, Ezekiel 38, read verse 8
through 12.
You get it? Go ahead and read it.
>> After many days, thou shall be visit. In
the latter years, thou shalt come into
the land that is brought back from the
sword and is gathered out of many people
against the mountains of Israel, which
shall have been always waste, but it is
brought forth out of the nations. They
shall dwell safe safely, all of them.
Thou shall send and come like a storm.
Thou shalt be like a cloud to cover the
land. Thou and all thy bands and many
people with thee. Thus sayeth the Lord
God, it shall also come to pass that at
that same time shall things come into
thy mind. Thou shalt think in evil
thought
>> and thou shalt say, I will go up to the
land of unwalled villages. I will go to
them that are at rest, that dwell
safely, all of them dwelling without
wall and having neither bars nor gates.
>> Yeah. So that evil thought came into
their mind was Satan, he in the pit at
that time, you know. So you can have an
evil thought on your own.
That's that's all I got on you.
Thank you, brother Jerome. You got your
background. If you could put that up.
Um, Sister Deborah, we going to do a
time check.
>> Uh, yes. The time is 8:10.
Um, Robert Doch asked for you to explain
Romans 7.
Uh, there's no verses uh given, but Ro
to explain Romans 7 about sinning after
baptism.
We're going to ask brother Julius to uh
address that question. Brother Julius,
>> yes. Romans 7 does not deal with sinning
after baptism.
It does not address that. It it it
addresses the commandments of God,
identifying what sin is and walking in
the spirit remind and also reminding us
that sin is ever present. has nothing to
do with sinning after baptism.
But I can give you a scripture in
Hebrews the 10th chapter. If you sin
willfully, let's go to that Romans the
10th chapter.
Cuz there we're not talking about
sinning inadvertently. There's not a man
that's not going to sin inadvertently.
Let's go to Hebrews the 10th chapter.
And after you get baptized and you know
the truth and you understand the plan of
God and you still want to sin
even after you baptize Romans 10 and
read verse 26
>> for if we sin willfully after that we
have received the knowledge of the truth
there remainth no more sacrifice for
sin.
>> Go ahead. but a certain fearful looking
for of judgment and fiery indignation
which shall devour the adversaries.
>> So that's the lake of fire. If we sin
willfully after you baptize and you sin
willfully that means you really didn't
believe in what you was doing and you
didn't take it serious. That's the only
thing that I can think of. But because
you didn't give us no scripture, but the
whole chapter of Romans, the seventh
chapter does not explicitly deal with
baptism after sin.
I hope that helped. Trey,
>> thank you, brother Julius, for that
answer. We we certainly hope it helps.
Uh, Sister Deborah, we'll move on to the
next question.
>> Moving on. Jennifer Love asks, "Can
someone get baptized at any camp that
they choose?"
>> Well, you know, I cannot read where you
must be baptized at a certain class. Uh,
but let's go to uh Acts the 19th chapter
and we're going to look at something
there. Acts 19
and 4 and 5.
Acts 19:4 and5. Go ahead.
>> Then said Paul, John, verily bapt bapti
baptized with the baptism of repentance,
saying unto the people that they shall
believe on him which shall come after
him that is on Christ Jesus.
>> And when they heard this, they were
baptized in the name of the Lord Jesus.
>> So yeah, you get baptized in the name of
the Lord Jesus. But as the guest caller
said a few questions ago that if you a
male, you should be cir you must be
circumcised in order to get baptized
because you are coming up under the
blood of Jesus and entering into that
covenant that is established in his
blood. Now let's go to uh Acts the 2
chapter and look at something there
again. Acts two and we're gonna read
verses 37 to 41. Go ahead when you get
it, brother.
>> 37.
Now when they heard this, they were
pricricked in their hearts and said unto
Peter and to the rest of the apostles,
>> brethren,
>> what shall we do? Then Peter said unto
them, "Repent and be baptized every one
of you in the name of Jesus Christ for
the remission of sin.
>> Receive the gift of the Holy Ghost."
>> That's right. So this is what we are to
do is get baptized in the name of Jesus,
repent, turn away from our sins. But
again, if you a male, you must needs be
circumcised.
And if you are a female, you you cannot
come and get baptized when you are in
that time of uncleanliness. So, you
know, we we have to follow what it is
that the Lord has in place. Um,
let's see who our Passover is. Let's go
to First Corinthians 5 and 7. 1
Corinthians 5 and 7.
Go ahead when you get it.
>> Purge out therefore the old leaven that
ye may be a new lamb as ye are
unleavened. For even Christ our Passover
is sacrificed for us.
>> So Christ is our Passover. And if we are
to come up under that blood, we have to
do what is written in Exodus 12, the
ordinance of the Passover. In order to
partake of that Passover, we must be
circumcised. Whether you be Israel or
anybody else,
uh we must be circumcised. Also, that is
written under the covenant that's
established with Abraham in Genesis 17.
10-14
about
being circumcised. If you a male, in
order to partake of the Passover, you
must needs be circumcised.
And getting baptized, which is partaking
of his coming under his blood, you must
need be circumcised. That's all I got on
that. Uh if anybody would like to add if
not we'll move on sister Deborah to the
next question.
>> Yes. Moving on. Time out Houston says so
the Bible says only eight people were on
Earth 4,000 years ago. Does this support
evolution at all?
>> We're going to ask Brother Julius to
answer that question. Brother Julius
>> time out Houston. This sounds like a
creation versus evolution question. Uh
the 4,000 years ago, 4,000 first of all,
it was more the people than that that
was on the earth. Uh 4,000 years ago,
Adam and Eve was the first man and woman
and out of them the whole earth were
created and then there was a creation
that was drowned and then Noah and his
sons replenished the earth whenever it
was. The Bible does not support
evolution. The Bible supports the
absolute word of God to show you where
things come from. Let me show you what
the Bible teaches that evolution does
not. Evolution is man's theory. Let's go
to St. John the first chapter.
Man is trying to put a date on
everything. No. St. John the first
chapter. Read verse one and then we
going to skip to verse three. Tenzel.
In the beginning was the word.
The word was with God and the word was
God.
>> Uhhuh.
>> The same was in the beginning with God.
>> Now the Father, that's the Father and
the Son. Go ahead.
>> And all things were made by him, and
without him was not anything made that
was made. This right here tells me that
if there's a creation, it has to be a
creator.
The Bible supports the that God created
everything seen and unseen. So it
doesn't matter what man thinks or how
man feel. It's what the word of God
says. And the book is concluded that
Deuteronomy 8 chapter man should not
live by bread alone but by every word
that proceed out of the mouth of God. So
I don't do uh evolution. I do the
creation by the God of Israel. And the
book says all things were made by him
and without him was not anything made
that was made.
>> Right.
>> That's all I got on that.
>> Thank you, brother J.
>> Guest caller.
>> The way God do things, it was always
done. You know, just like if there was
evolution like man said from eight to a
man, then you have to ask this, you need
to go to the zoo and ask them out there
what happened to you guys. You ain't
supposed to be eight. You're supposed to
be man,
>> right?
>> But there is the evolution that's going
on.
Every butterfly is a caterpillar first.
>> Yes.
>> And every frog I toad is a tadpole
first. Yes.
>> Do they evolve from a caterpillar to the
butterfly?
Evolve from a tadpole to a frog or toad.
But then that evolution have been on
from day one.
>> Day one.
>> Everything is
I just want to throw that in.
>> Absolutely. How long do it take a How
long do it take a gorilla to turn into a
ape to turn into a man?
That is
>> That's right.
That is not God's evolution.
>> It's not happening.
>> That's right.
>> Every man Every man would be born at
first, wouldn't it?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Okay.
>> All right, Sister D, we're gonna move on
to the next question.
>> Yes. Next question. Robert Doch says
uh it is said that God puts no more on
us than we can bear. What if it what if
it is Satan
putting something on us?
>> We're going to ask the guest caller to
address that question. Guest caller.
First thing is
Satan can't do
Satan can only do what God allow him to
do or command him to do. So if Satan is
messing with you, you need to check your
household
or check yourself because God
created Satan and he is a ministering
spirit. Let's look at Job and let's look
at how how how uh the Lord invited uh
Job uh uh uh Satan to Job and look at
the limitation the Lord put on it. Job 1
and we're gonna read 6-12.
>> Job 1:6-12.
>> Now there was a day when the sons of God
came to present themselves before the
Lord. And Satan came also among them.
And the Lord said unto Satan, "Whence
comest thou?" Then Satan answered the
Lord and said, "From going to and fro in
the earth, and from walking up and down
in it." And the Lord said unto Satan,
"Hast thou consider my servant Job, that
there is none like him in the earth, a
perfect and an upright man, one that
fearth God, and it doeth evil."
Then Satan answered the Lord, and said,
"But do Job fear God? But no,
hast not thou made an hedge about him,
and about his house, and about all that
he hath on every side? Thou hast blessed
the work of his hands, and his substance
increased in the land.
But put forth thy hand now, and touch
all that he have, and he will curse thee
to thy face."
And the Lord said unto Satan, Behold,
all that he hath is in thy power, only
upon himself, put not forth thy hand. So
Satan went forth from the presence of
the Lord.
>> Now that's verse 12.
>> That was the end of 12.
>> Listen, notice how that conversation
went. He told uh Satan, "Okay, then
you can put forth his hand and touch his
uh uh uh uh his his material. You can
destroy everything, but I don't want you
touching him." And Satan didn't touch
Job. But go to Job the 2 chapter and
read 1 through3 because this is real
interesting. Job 2:es 1-3.
Again, there was a day when the sons of
God came to present themselves before
the Lord. And Satan came also.
>> And Satan came also among them to
present himself before the Lord. And the
Lord said unto Satan, "From when comest
thou?" And Satan answered the Lord and
said, "From going to and fro in the
earth, and from walking up and down in
it." And the Lord said unto Satan, "Has
thou considered my servant Job, that
there is none like him in the earth, a
perfect and an upright man, one that
fear God, and is sheth evil? And still
he holdeth fast his integrity, although
thou movest me against him to destroy
him without a cause."
Wait a minute. Thou move who against him
destroy
>> move is me against him.
>> That's right. Because Satan is nothing
but a finger of God. And if the Lord
didn't and Satan can't touch you, if the
Lord don't want you to be touched,
>> right?
>> Let's go into Psalms.
Let's go into Psalms 34:7.
Read it when you get there.
>> Psalm 4 and 7. Psalms 34 and 7.
>> The angel of the Lord encamp round about
them that fear him and deliverth them.
>> Now that angel is always there.
And the only time Satan can get to you
if you get God angry at you. Let me give
you some quick example. First, go to s
uh 2 Samuel the 24th chapter. Read verse
1 and skip down and read verse 9 through
12.
>> 1st Samuel 24.
>> Yep. Verses 1 and then verses 9- 12.
And it came to pass when Saul was
returned from following the Philistines
that it was told him saying, "Behold,
David is in the wilderness of Indigo."
Skip down to verse uh nine.
>> Yeah. And continue.
>> And David said to Saul, "Wherefore here
is thou men's word, saying, Behold,
David seekest thou hurt.
Behold, this day thy eyes have seen how
the Lord have delivered thee to thee
into my hand in the cave. And some b to
kill thee, but my eyes spare thee. And I
said, I would not put forth my hand
against my Lord, for he is the Lord
anointed.
>> Now,
did you finish that?
>> That was the end of 10.
Okay. Well, look, uh uh uh what was how
far did you did you keep reading? Uh did
did you finish that? Was that the end of
10? I told you to read the 12.
>> Okay, let me keep going.
>> So, moreover, my father's seat. Yes. See
the skirt of thy robe in my hand. For in
that I cut off the skirt of thy robe,
and kill thee not. But know thou and see
that there is neither evil nor
transgression in my hand, and I have not
sinned.
>> Wait a minute. Uh I I think
>> Samuel
>> 2 Samuel 24.
>> Oh, was 2 Samuel 24.
>> Yes.
>> 2 Samuel 24.
>> Okay.
>> And verse one.
>> And then skip down to verse 9.
2 Samuel 24 verse 1 and then 9 to2.
>> Yeah.
>> And the anger and again the anger of the
Lord was kindled against Israel. And he
moved David against them to say go
number Israel and Judah Judah.
>> Verses 9 through 12. And Joab gave up
the sum of the number of the people unto
the king. And there were in Israel
800,000 valiant men that drew the sword.
And the men of Judah were 500,000
men. And David heart smoked him after
that he had numbered the people. And
David said unto the Lord, I have sinned
of greatly and that I have done. And now
I beseech thee, oh Lord, take away the
iniquity of thy servant, for I have done
very foolishly.
For when David was up in the morning,
the word of the Lord came unto the
prophet Gad, David seer, saying, Well,
go and say unto David, thus said the
Lord, I offer thee three things, choose
thee one of them, that I may do it unto
thee.
So now, even though David was pleading,
God let him know, "I'mma do something to
you." And he did. But he started off
said God was angry with Israel. Didn't
he say that?
>> Yeah. Yes, sir.
>> He He killed a lot of Israelite, but he
didn't lay a finger on David. So, and he
said God moved him. Didn't Didn't it
read that? That God moved him to count
Isra County Israel.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Let's see how he did it. Let's go into 1
Chronicles the 21st chapter
[Music]
and read verses
1.
>> 1 Chronicles 21 chapter 21 and verse
one.
>> 1 Chronicles
>> 1 Chronicles 21 verse one.
>> New story.
>> And Satan stood up against Israel and
provoked David to number Israel.
Wait a minute now. Who is the one that
stood up against Israel? Satan or God?
>> Satan.
>> God is the one that was angry at s at at
Israel. Did we read that?
>> We read that.
>> What did he do? He sent Satan
to make him count Israel,
>> right?
>> The Lord said Israel wouldn't be
counted.
>> So now, who gave an order there?
>> God did.
>> God did. Let's
go to one more place and that'll be the
end of it. Let's go into Psalms chapter
78.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Read verse 42 and 43 and skip down and
read verse 49.
>> Psalm 78 42 43 and 49. Brother Tanzel,
>> they remember not his hand, nor the day
when he delivered them from the enemy.
How he had wrought his signs in Egypt
and his wonders in the field of Zoan.
>> Now, these signs he put in Egypt, that's
when he really destroyed Egypt. Now, how
did he do that? Keep reading.
This 49 49 49
How did he do that? Go ahead.
>> He cast upon them the fierceness of his
anger, wrath, and indignation, and
trouble by sending evil angels among
them.
>> So now, who is the one that sent the
evil evil angels among the Egyptians?
>> The Lord did.
>> So now, Satan can't do nothing to you
if the Lord don't want him to do nothing
to you.
But if you do wrong and he come up on
you and go upside your head, that's
because you did wrong in the sight of
God and he sent Satan to go up on your
head. You I just want you to understand
that
people feel the wrong one. You don't
feel Satan. He's a ministering spirit.
You feel the one that created him.
That's all I have to say.
>> Thank you guest caller for that clear
breakdown. Uh, sister Deborah, next
question.
>> Yes. Moving on. Uh, brother Anthony
Horsey asks for some enlightenment on
Galatians 4:es 8-10.
He says, "I had a brother who tried to
use this to defend Colossians 2 verse
16, saying we don't have to observe
these days."
We're gonna ask brother Jerome to shed
some light on that question. Brother
Jerome,
uh let's let's go read the verse that he
gave. We going to do um Galatians 4 8-10
first before before we deal with that.
Uh Colossians 2:16. Okay, Tanzel.
>> Galatians 4 8 through 10.
>> Yeah, go ahead and read. For how be it
then, when ye knew not God, ye did
service unto them which by nature are no
God. But now, after that ye have known
God, or rather are known of God, how
turn ye again to the weak, and beggarly
elements where unto ye desire again to
be in bondage,
>> who observe days and months, and times,
and years.
>> Okay.
Um, I know you you reading this verse
because you trying to
do away with the law, the laws of God,
>> but you have to understand that there's
another law that was added because of
sin.
Okay? Now, these laws that he telling
you, why you turning back to these beggy
elements, it's called the law of animal
sacrifices. Okay. Actually in uh Hebrews
the 10th church it said the law of burnt
offerings and sacrifices sacrifices for
sin. It's animal sacrifices.
>> Right.
>> Okay. They were turned into that for the
removal of their sin. But the blood of b
b b b b b b b b b b b b b b b b b b b b
b b b b b b b b b b b b b b b b b b bs
and goats can't remove sin. All right.
But the Lord had that law added because
he a merciful God. The wage of sin is
death.
If them animals don't die in our place,
we wouldn't be sitting here before you
and you wouldn't be asking this question
because you wouldn't be around. Neither
one of us would be around. So he added
that law until Jesus came the offering,
the sin offering that whose blood was
offered which can take away sin. All
right? So that's the law that we not
under. So when you read these verses,
these
Jews was telling these Gentiles to do
these things when these things were
nailed to the cross. What? Not the law
that teach you how to love your brother
and to love God with all your heart,
mind, soul, and strength, which is the
ten commandments. It was the law of
animal sacrifices because Jesus replaced
that because he became the ultimate
sacrifice
>> whose blood was shed that can take away
sin. Animal blood can't do that. All
right. So now
uh let's let's go uh and read that uh uh
I think it's Galatians 3. Let's go to
Galatians 3 and read verse 19.
Because a lot of people think this
talking about the ten commandments and
it's not.
When you get it, go ahead and read.
>> So wherefore then serve the law, it was
added because of transgression to the
seed should come to whom the promise was
made.
>> That's good. That's good. It said,
"Wherefore then serve the law it was
added."
>> See, you can't ignore that. It was
added. Why was it added? It was added
because of transgression. Well, what is
transgression? Transgression is sin. And
sin is a transgression of God's law.
Them ten commandments. When you broke
them ten commandments, the Lord added
this law which is called animal
sacrifices.
Okay. Skip down to verse 23 and read it
to the 24.
>> But before to the 25. Read it to the 25.
Go ahead.
>> But before faith came, we were kept
under the law. shut up under the faith
which should afterwards be revealed.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Wherefore the law was our school master
to bring us unto Christ that we might be
justified by faith.
>> Uhhuh.
>> But after that faith is come. We are no
longer under a school master.
For ye are all the children of God.
>> That's good, brother. That's good. So we
talking sacrificial law here. That was a
law that was added when you broke the
ten commandments,
>> right?
>> The blood of animals was shed instead of
your blood being shed. Okay? So, now
let's deal with um
let's go to Acts the 20th chapter. I
think you you mentioned that too cuz if
you read the whole chapter, we ain't got
time. If you read all of Hebrews the
10th chapter, it'll explain that
sacrificial law in depth. But for the
time, we we we're not going to do that.
Okay? But on your own time, read that
Hebrews 10th chapter. It explains what
the sacrificial law is. All right? We
not under it anymore. All right? So now,
let's go to that Acts 20. I'm sorry.
Uh yeah, I think you gave Acts No, you
gave Colossians.
>> Colossians 2 verse 16.
>> Yeah. Read Colossians 2:16.
Go ahead.
>> Let no man therefore judge you in meat
or in drink or in respect of an holy day
or of the new moon or of the Sabbath
days.
>> Okay. So I I I know that sound like Paul
telling you we ain't got to keep the
holy days and and the Sabbath, but
that's an error. All right. Because Paul
gonna tell you in his own writings that
he keeping the the holy days and the
Sabbaths.
So if he's still keeping them long after
Jesus died and rose and sat down on the
right hand of the father in heaven, if
Paul's still doing this, you know, but
he telling you not to do it, then he a
hypocrite. And he not a hypocrite cuz
he's still keeping them cuz he know they
still good. Okay. So now let let's let's
show you that that Paul is still keeping
them long after Jesus is back in heaven.
All right. So let's go to uh now let's
go to Acts 20 and read verse 16.
Just just 16. Tanzel
go ahead when you get it.
For Paul had determined to sail by
Ephesus because he would not spend the
time in Asia, for he hasted, if it were
possible for him, to be at Jerusalem the
day of Pentecost.
By all means, he need to get back to
keep the holy day of Pentecost. That's
God's one one of God's holy day,
Pentecost. Okay. So now he also kept
continued to keep the Sabbath day which
is Saturday.
So let's go to that uh 18th chapter of
Acts and read verse 1-4.
When you get it, go ahead and read.
After these things, Paul departed from
Athens and came to Corinth, and found a
certain Jew named Aquilla, born in
Pontis, lately came from Italy with his
wife Priscilla, because that Claudius
had commanded all Jews to depart from
Rome, and came unto them, and because he
was of the same craft, and he abode with
them, and wroth, for by their occupation
they were tent makers.
And he reasoned in the synagogues every
Sabbath and persuaded the Jews and the
Greeks.
>> He prayed, persuaded Jews
and the Greeks. Every Sabbath. This is
long after Jesus went back to heaven.
Okay?
>> Because the Sabbath is still good. All
right. One more place. Let's go to 1
Corinthians 11th chapter. This the last
place.
1 Corinthians 11th chapter.
>> Yeah. This is once again long after
Jesus went back to heaven.
>> This is the instructions that Paul is
giving us from our Lord and Savior Jesus
Christ. All right.
Pick it up at verse one. Then we going
to skip.
>> Be ye followers of me even as I also am
of Christ. Skip down and read verse 23-
26.
>> For I have received of the Lord that
which also I deliver unto you. That the
Lord Jesus the same night in which he
was betrayed took bread. And when he had
given thanks, he broke it and said,
"Take, eat. This is my body which is
broken for you. This do in remembrance
of me." Mhm.
>> After the same manner also he took the
cup when he had sucked saying this cup
is the new testament in my blood.
>> It's the new testament in my blood.
Okay. This is an instruction Paul
getting from Jesus to to give unto us.
Go ahead.
>> This do ye as of as ye drink it in
remembrance of me.
>> Uhhuh. For as often as ye eat this bread
and drink this cup, ye do show the
Lord's death till he come.
>> And this is the Passover. That's another
God, one of God's holy days that we
still supposed to be keeping.
>> Okay?
>> And so there's a specific date when we
supposed to do it. The Lord established
that in Leviticus the 23rd chapter. You
can read that on your own. It gives you
the specific date. You keep it once a
year. That's Passover. Same thing with
the Pentecost. All right? and the
Sabbath day you keep
uh every week on Saturday. Every week.
That's all I got.
>> Thank you, brother Jerome. Um sister,
>> what was the last scripture you read?
>> Um
1 Corinthians the 11th chapter uh
dealing with the Passover
verse one and I skipped and read verse
23- 26.
Okay.
Reason I ask is because I'mma put him in
a lesson. Go ahead.
>> Praise the Lord in Jesus name.
>> Yes, sir.
All right, Sister Deborah. Next
question.
>> Yes. Moving on. China the Israelites
says, "I'm still having trouble fully
understanding Daniel 12 11 and 12. Is it
referring to 70 AD and the fall of Msada
73 AD or a future prophecy of the
tribulation?
>> We're going to ask the guest caller to
shed some light on that question. Guest
caller.
>> No, it's not it's not referring to uh 70
AD or 73 AD.
Uh because in 7 AD
that's when uh uh uh Titus took our
forefathers, the real Israelites
out of the land and none of them left.
They scattered and 73 Msada is when they
took Edom because when Israel left, Edom
moved on up and took over the whole
thing.
and to give you and to show and I'm
going to show you that something that
never happened in either one of those
times. First, let's go into uh uh uh
into uh Matthew the 24th chapter.
We're going to read verse 15
and then I tell you and we going to skip
>> Matthew 24 and 15.
So when ye therefore shall see the
abomination of desolation spoken of by
Daniel the prophet, stand in the holy
place, who so readeth, let him
understand.
>> We didn't see that in 70 AD, did we?
>> Neither did we 73. Skip down to verse
21. Read 21 and 22.
For then shall be great tribulations,
such as was not since the beginning of
the world to this time, no nor ever
shall be. And except those days should
be shortened, there shall no flesh be
saved. But for the elect's sake, those
days shall be shortened.
>> Now skip down to verse 29. Read verse 29
and 30.
Immediately after the tribulation of
those days shall the sun be darkened,
and the moon shall not give her life,
and the stars shall fall from heaven,
and the powers of the heavens shall be
shaken.
And then shall appear the sign of the
Son of Man in heaven. And then shall all
the tribes of the earth mourn, and they
shall see the Son of Man coming in the
clouds of heaven with power and great
glory.
>> So now Jesus didn't come in 70 AD. He
didn't come in 73 AD. But right here in
long uh Daniel's 12 11 and 12 that's
talking about when they setting up the
abomination of desolation
after his time Jesus going to come
because he is going to put an end to his
rule. So now that's future that's
talking about the great tribulation.
That's all I have to say.
>> Thank you guest caller for that answer.
We hope you got some understanding
sister Deborah. We'll go to our next
question.
>> Next question. Patrice asks, "Are the
spiritual gifts spoken of in Corinthians
7- 11 still existence in modern people?
Or were they only existing in historical
Christians in the time this particular
part of the Bible was written?"
We're going to ask brother Julius and
the guest caller to chime in on this
question. Brother Julius,
>> let's go to that first Corinthians
chapter 12 tenzil and begin read at
seven uh because it it it includes it's
always been spiritual gifts but it
included that time and on into this
time.
Go ahead brother. 1 Corinthians 12 and
verse um
Read verse one. Just verse one and we'll
skip. Go ahead.
>> Now concerning spiritual gifts,
brethren, I would not have you ignorant.
>> So now skip down to verse four and go
ahead.
>> But now there are diversities of gifts
for the same spirit.
>> Look what Paul look how Paul said. Now
there are there are which mean it exist.
There are diversities of uh uh uh
>> gifts
>> gifts but the same spirit. Skip down to
verse six and go ahead.
>> And there are diversities of operations
but it is the same God which workketh
all in all.
>> Right.
Skip down. Uh continue. Continue.
>> For the manifestation of the spirit is
given to every man to profit with all.
>> Uhhuh.
For to one
>> For to one is given by the spirit the
word of wisdom.
>> Solomon was a wise man. Go ahead. The
wisest man. Go ahead.
>> To another the word of knowledge by the
same spirit.
>> Go ahead.
>> And to another faith by the same spirit.
>> And faith you got to you have always had
to believe in God. Go ahead. and to
another the gifts of healing by the same
Spirit.
>> Come on.
>> To another the working of miracles,
to another prophecy,
to another disc the discerning of
spirits.
To another diverse kinds of tongues.
>> That show that show that happened on the
day of Pentecost. Go ahead.
>> To another the interpretation of
tongues.
>> Same thing. Day of Pentecost. Now skip
down to verse 18. I I'm I'm going
through these scriptures, these
scriptures to show you that the Lord has
always had these things in place in
different times and then especially in
the New Testament time when the church
really begin to grow. Verse 18,
>> but now have God set the members every
one of them in the body as it have
pleased him.
>> That is the body, this is the body of
Christ, the church. verse 25
>> that there should be no schism in the
body but that the members should have
the same care one for another.
>> So all of this these things uh uh he
gave some prophets and he gave some
evangelists and he gave some h pastors
and stuff like this. Uh so therefore
these things have always been in place
for the body of Christ especially in the
new testament times. That's what these
things are all about. That the body that
the the church can grow and the gospel
of the kingdom of God can be spread.
Guest caller
just have one place.
Ephesians 4 7-11.
>> Ephesians 4 7-11.
>> Okay. Ephesians 4.
But unto every one of us is giving grace
according to the measure of the gift of
Christ.
So wherefore he said, when he ascended
up on high, and he led captivity
captive, and gave gifts unto men, but
now that he ascended, what is it but
that he also descended first unto the
lower parts of the earth?
And he that descended is the same also
that ascended up far above all heavens,
that he might feel all things.
and he gave some apostles and some
prophets and some evangelists and some
pastors and teachers.
>> So that's it in a nutshell. He's still
giving gifts.
>> That's all I have to say.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you guest caller and brother
Julius for that answer. Sister Deborah
time check. And it looks like we're
going into new territory. Yes, the time
is 8:52. We are now into tonight's Q&A
for Wednesday, August the 13th, 2025.
Shaquila Au jobi asked in Galatians 5 22
and 23, the fruits of the spirit are
revealed to us. Could negative emotions
such as anger, sadness, jealousy,
hatred, and envy
be reflections of evil spirits that made
a home in us?
>> Yes, we're going to open that up to the
panel, but yes, the answer is
absolutely. And if you bag up to verse
16, he's telling us to walk in the
spirit. Can you read that, brother
Tanzel?
>> But this I say then, walk in the spirit
and you should not fulfill the lust of
the flesh.
>> So all of those things that you
mentioned,
those things are mentioned in verse 17
on read skip down to verse 19 and read
it, brother. Go ahead. But now the works
of the flesh are manifested, which are
these: adultery, fornication,
uncleanness, lasciviousness,
idolatry, witchcraft, hatred, variance,
emulation, wrath, strife, sedition,
heresies,
murders, drunkenness, revailing, and
such light of the which I tell you
before as I have also O told you in time
past that they which do such things
should not inherit the kingdom of God.
>> So all of those things that I mentioned
are against the word of God and against
the laws of God. Read verse 22 one more
time.
But the fruit of the spirit is love,
joy,
peace, longsuffering,
gentleness, goodness, faith,
>> meekness. Go ahead. 23 and 24. And
that'll be it.
>> Meekness, temperance. Against such there
is no law. And they that are Christ have
crucified the flesh with their
affections and lust. and they crucified
the flesh and they are walking in the
spirit, walking in the word of God. This
is what they're doing. And so there is
no law with no penalty of the law as
long as you are a a lawabiding citizen.
>> Right?
>> So if anybody else would like to add, I
will move on to the next question.
Sister Deborah, let's move on. Moving
on. Humility Israel says in Psalms 90
verse 10. Was this verse a typo or what
am I missing?
>> We're going to read that Psalms 90:10
and open it up to the panel. Go ahead,
brother Tanzel. When you get it, go
ahead.
>> The days of our years are three score
years and 10. And if by reason of
strength they be four score years, yet
is their strength labor in sorrow. For
it is soon cut down and we fly away.
>> Open to the panel.
>> Thus,
no, that's not a typo.
It it means what it says. You the Lord
give you 70 years. He's just telling you
if you live past that, that's a
blessing. But still, as you still
getting older and you still gonna have
aches and pains and so on, such is life.
And then you live your life and then you
go to the grave.
>> That's right. Uh read that verse 12,
brother Tanzel, in that chapter
>> to teach us to number our days that we
may apply our hearts unto wisdom. So
that's what we should do while we're
living to count our days and to apply
our hearts to wisdom while we're living.
That's all I got on that. If anybody
else would like to add or we'll move on
to the next question.
>> I think one thing I think one thing we
better address because I know what he's
looking at.
>> Okay.
>> He said fly away.
>> Yeah. Right.
>> Okay. like
go to Genesis the third chapter and read
19.
>> Yes, sir. Genesis 3 and 19.
>> That's where you go fly away to.
>> Well, that's what happened when dust
when the wind blow dust.
>> Uh Genesis,
>> they talking about they talking about
going to heaven. I'mma show you where
you
>> Oh, okay.
>> Yeah.
What was that? Genesis 19.
>> Genesis 3 and19.
>> Genesis 3 and 19.
Okay.
In the sweat of thy face shalt thou eat
bread till thou return unto the ground.
For out of it was thou taken. For dust
thou are, and to dust shall thou return.
>> So use the term fly away was a metaphor.
They saying then you're gonna die and go
back to the ground.
>> Yes, sir.
>> That's all.
>> Hey, thus you are and on to dust shall
you return.
>> That is not a typo.
>> No. Uh, Sister Deborah, we may have time
for one more question. Sister Deborah,
bring it on.
>> All right, one more question. Uh,
Crystal Williams uh asks, "Could you uh
explain St. John 21
23 and 24. And they also want to know,
you probably can answer this one right
away. Uh, the book of St. John, was the
book of St. John written by John the
Baptist?
>> So, was the book Yeah. was the book of
St. uh, John written by John the
Baptist? and she wants you to explain
uh St. John 21
23 and 24.
>> Let's go to that St. John 21 23 and 24
and we'll address that question. Open it
up to the panel. Go ahead, brother
Tanzel.
>> Then went this saying abroad among the
brethren that that disciple should not
die. Yet Jesus said not unto him, he
shall not die. But if I will that he tar
till I come, what is that to thee? This
is the disciples that testify of these
things and wrote these things and we
know that his testimony is true.
>> Sister Deborah, can you repeat the
question again and we'll open it to the
panel.
>> Yes. She wants you to explain that uh
those two scriptures
and also was John St. John written by
John the Baptist
>> open to the panel.
>> Well, the first thing is he wasn't
saying that John was going to be here to
get until he come. We got we want to
back up a little bit and look at this
because when the Lord told uh John to go
with him, Peter seem to have taken some
issue and he is going to question God.
Okay, let's see uh uh where we can
start. Uh uh
let's see.
Cuz uh he told John, you know, go with
him.
Let's see.
[Music]
Is that 20?
Yeah, maybe it is. Let's see what it
says.
>> Started,
>> you know, reading verse 19. What Jesus
spoke to John started verse 19.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Well, this spake he signifying by what
death he should he should glorify God.
And when he had spoken this, he said
unto unto him, "Follow me." Then Peter
turned.
>> Go ahead.
>> Then Peter turning about seeth the
disciple whom Jesus loved following,
which also leaned on his breast at
supper, and said, Lord, which is he that
betrayeth thee?
And Peter seeing him said to Jesus,
"Lord, and what shall this man do?" And
Jesus,
>> see, he was out of place. He was out of
place for asking that question. You
understand?
>> That's jealousy. He told John, turn him
and said, "Follow me." Peter won't
answer.
In other words, when he saw that, he
said to Jesus, "Lord, what shall this
man do?" That wasn't his business. Do
you understand?
But go ahead and read
>> what Jesus said unto him. If I will that
he tell me till I come, what is that to
thee? Follow thou me.
Now he telling him, look, if I tell him
to wait here until I come back, what's
this for you? Then he turned around and
told the guy to follow me.
He didn't say that he's going to live
forever. What was the what was how much
more that what what verse did they ask
you? 23
>> 23 and 24.
>> Then let's pay attention to 23. Now go
ahead.
>> Then went this saying abroad among the
brethren
that that disciple should not die. Yet
Jesus said not unto him and he shall not
die. But if I will that he tar till I
come, what is that to thee?
So that's all he's saying. He not saying
the man going to stay. He telling Peter
told Peter, "Look, if I if I tell him to
uh uh stay here uh don't live until I
die, well, that ain't none of your
business." That's all he's telling me.
Okay? Because Peter took issue because
uh he wanted to know why God or Jesus
was telling John to follow him
instead of asking him to follow him.
So that's all it is. You're just putting
Peter in his place. Look, it ain't none
of your business. If I told him to wait
until I come back, what's that to you?
Now, for the other part of it, John the
Baptist did not write uh the book of
John because John the Baptist,
he was killed soon as Jesus started his
ministry.
And John the Baptist is still dead. So
he couldn't have rose him rose raised
him from the dead to write the book of
revelation or the book of John or
anything.
That's all I have to say.
>> Thank you guest caller for that answer,
sister Deborah. Time check.
>> 9:04
>> 9:04. We'd like to thank everyone who
sent in all of these great questions
from around the world. We took joy in
answering them and pray that you were
edified. If you didn't hear your
question answered tonight, there's no
need to resubmit your question. It will
be answered in the order that it was
given and we will pick up where we left
off next week. So, please join us next
week for ILG's Q&A and be strengthened
in the Lord. Brother Tanzel, close us
out. Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven. Give us this day our daily
bread, and forgive us of our debts as we
forgive our debt towards, and lead us
not into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom and the
power and the glory.